Will Oursler Papers
Will Oursler Papers
- Manuscripts (original accession)
  - Books
    - The Prudential (with Earl Chapin May)
      - Carbon, pp. 1-490 and appendix, 4 folders (Box 30)
      - Drafts
        - Opening chapters and notes (Box 30)
        - I (Box 30)
        - II (Box 30)
        - Middle chapters and notes (Box 31)
        - I (Box 31)
        - II (Box 31)
        - Final chapters and notes, and miscellaneous pages (Box 31)
        - Tentative outlines (Box 31)
    - The Road to Faith
      - Final Draft pp. 1-198, 4 folders (Box 31)
      - Draft pp. 1-198, 4 folders (Box 32)
      - Incomplete preliminary draft with revisions, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - To The Commissioner: Confidential
      - Original pages and papers, pp. 1-77 (Box 32)
      - Carbon (typescript) pp. 1-237, 4 folders (Box 32)
    - The Trial of Vincent Doon or Beyond Reasonable Doubt
      - Final Draft pp. 1-224, 4 folders (Box 33)
      - Drafts pp. 1-225 and unnumbered pages, 5 folders (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous Outlines for Books (Box 33)
  - Plays
    - The Blessed Damozel or Cloud of Glory or The Lady Weeps
      - Incomplete drafts and notes (Box 34)
    - Neighborhood House
      - Incomplete Draft (Box 34)
      - Drafts by Acts (Box 34)
      - Carbon (Box 34)
      - Notes (Box 34)
      - Outlines (Box 34)
    - Queen Bee
      - Drafts and Notes, 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Carbon Copies, 4 copies (Box 35)
      - Mimeographed Copy (Box 35)
  - Poems
    - "Baker Street Fever" (Box 36)
  - Scripts
    - Radio (Box 36)
    - Television
      - International Police Series (Oursler, ed.), untitled pilot (Box 36)
      - "The Case of the Happy Jewel Robbers" (Box 36)
      - "Private Eye", ideas for presentation (Box 36)
      - "Stanza" (Box 36)
      - "Terror" or "Center Street", notes and plans (Box 36)
      - Miscellaneous ideas (Box 36)
  - Short Stories
    - "Bigamy Trial of the Bogus Prince" (Box 37)
    - "A Case of Unwritten Law" (Box 37)
    - "Chinese Riddle" (Box 37)
    - "Corpse in the Berkshire and the Jig-Saw Puzzle Clue" (Box 37)
    - "The Crash" (Box 37)
    - "The Cuffs" (Box 37)
    - "The Curse of the Kingsway" (Box 37)
    - "The Draw" (Box 37)
    - "Hula Homicide" or "Shadow in Paradise" (Box 37)
    - "The Ladies in Black" and "Deed Without A Name" (Box 37)
    - "Last Word" or "No Tickee" (Box 37)
    - "Murder Without a Corpse" or "The Case Without a Corpse" or "The Crime Without a Corpse" or "Vanished Lady" (Box 37)
    - "Payoff" (Box 37)
    - "Portrait of a Hood" (Box 37)
    - "The Shadow and the Shadowed" or "The Perfect Out" or "Alias Eve" (Box 37)
    - "The Shining Limosine" [sic] (Box 37)
    - "Special Treatment" (Box 37)
    - "Still of the Night" or "Quiet Moment" (Box 37)
    - "The Untold Story of Martha" (Box 38)
    - "The Vanishing Hands of Mrs. Davenport" (with Fulton Oursler, pseud. Anthony Abbot) (Box 38)
    - "The Waiter, the Song, and the Girl" (Box 38)
    - "Winston Churchill's Strange Case" (Box 38)
  - Unidentified pages and notes
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
  - Manuscripts of others
    - "True Life Dramas" by Victor Boesen (Box 38)
- Published material (original accession)
  - Article about (Box 1)
  - Articles by (Box 1)
  - Books by
    - Father Flanagan of Boy's Town, Punjabi, Chinese and Marathi language editions (Box 1)
    - Folio on Florence White, Spanish (Latin American) edition (Box 1)
  - Books by others (Box 1)
  - Magazines (Box 1)
  - Newspapers (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings by (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Reports (Box 1)
- Correspondence (1967 accession)
  - A-W, 1965-1967; undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence of others, undated; Nebel, John "Long John" (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 1)
- Subject files (1967 accession)
  - Reference material
    - for "Automation" article, 1964-1965; undated (Box 1)
    - Crime - juvenile (Star-Commonwealth), 1949-1951; undated (Box 1)
    - Crime - Royal Canadian, 1949-1950; undated (Box 1)
    - for Dr. Robert F. Thomas article, 1956; undated (Box 1)
    - for The Gift of Healing, undated (Box 1)
    - Scandinavian stories, 1964; undated (Box 1)
    - Teamster story, 1957-1958; undated (Box 2)
    - Traffic and parking story, 1964; undated (Box 2)
    - Witchcraft, 1966; undated (Box 2)
    - World political picture, post-World War II, radio liberation, 1955; undated (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook material
    - 1955 (Box 2)
    - Undated (Box 2)
- Manuscripts (1967 accession)
  - Articles
    - Belgrade backwash, 1962; undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 2)
    - Check up on your checks, undated; typescript (Box 2)
    - Courage with common sense, 1951; typescript (Box 2)
    - Dryden, John Fairfield, 1958; typescript and carbon copies (Box 2)
    - Ferment in suburban faith, undated; carbon copy (Box 2)
    - Is heaven a myth?, 1967; undated; holograph, typescript, carbon copies, and first proof (Box 2)
    - Million dollar fence, undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 2)
    - Miracle on Elm Street, undated; typescript (Box 2)
    - My message to America (Billy Graham story), 1953; undated; holograph, typescript, carbon copies (Box 2)
    - Mr. Hoover's magic trunk, undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 3)
    - Otto Bettmann, archivist of the world, undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 3)
    - Revival on the campus: the 'God-Is-Dead' boomerang, 1966; undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 3)
    - Rugged road to adventure (Lowell Thomas story), 1964-1965; undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 3)
    - Shopping for courtesy, 1956; typescript copies (Box 3)
    - Should we celebrate Christmas in our public schools?, 1966; undated; holograph, typescript, carbon copies, first proof (Box 3)
    - Sidewalk savagery must end, 1960; typescript, carbon, and xerox copies (Box 4)
    - Sidewalk savagery must end, 1960; notes, correspondence, research material (Box 4)
    - So you want to buy a boat, undated; holograph, typescript, carbon copies (Box 4)
    - Stained glass country club, or house of God?, undated; xerox copy (Box 5)
    - The star above these hills, undated; typescript and carbon copies (Box 5)
    - We gave our youth a chore, 1940; typescript and carbon copies (Box 5)
    - World War II
      - We capture an island, 1945; typescript copy (Box 5)
      - We kissed her goodbye twice, undated; carbon copy (Box 5)
  - Books
    - Murder Memo, 1950; undated; photographs and printed material (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets
    - for Academy of Religion and Mental Health, undated; holograph and typescript copies (Box 5)
    - Players Club bulletin (published), 1967; typescript copy (Box 5)
  - Plays
    - Clouds of Glory, undated; original draft; holograph, typescript, carbon copies (Box 5)
    - Revue, N.Y.N.Y., undated; typescript copy (Box 5)
  - Poetry
    - "Men of might", undated; holograph copy (Box 5)
    - "Ode to the River Charles", undated; typescript copy (Box 5)
    - Sonnet, 1936; typescript copy (Box 5)
  - Short stories
    - "The girl, the waiter, and the song", undated; typescript copy (Box 5)
    - "The amateur", undated; typescript and copies (Box 5)
  - Unidentified
    - Fragments (Box 5)
- Published material (1967 accession)
  - Articles
    - About (Box 5)
    - By others, "Twenty Questions", 1940-1942 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - About (Box 5)
- Correspondence (1974 accession)
  - 1964-1974 (Box 1)
- Writings (1974 accession)
  - Research material, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Research material, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - Outlines (Box 3)
  - Rough drafts, 9 folders (Box 3)
  - Rough drafts, 12 folders (Box 4)
  - Rough drafts, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Typescripts, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Galleys, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Galleys, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Page proofs (Box 6)
  - Paste-ups (Box 6)
  - Stories, 11 folders (Box 6)
  - Book (Box 7)